

Infos

- ▶ 29 years old
- Driver's License

Contact

- **■** sahriyarm@gmail.com
- 1 +14086096704
- S shahriyar.mammadov

About Me

Young man with +9 years of work experience in 6 countries in 7 big companies in various positions starting from engineering to management, sales. Early global citizen of world, valuable for companies whose target is to grow by investing on out-of-box thinking people. Love, focus,

Shahriyar MAMMADOV MBA MSc Lets build world without borders!

IT Security Cloud Computing System Engineering Network Engineering

For more details, check my online resume: www.doyoubuzz.com/shahriyar-mammadov

EXPERIENCE

Devops

OpenGov • January 2019 to April 2019



- Managing security of OpenGov's cloud infrastructure
- Improving the automation and cost efficiency of Kubernetes clusters in production
- Investigate and implement a service mesh technology (e.g. Istio) for improving observability and security, advanced routing, and fault injection for microservices running in Kubernetes

Devops

OpenGov • September 2018 to December 2018



- Building software and managing highly available sotware as a service
- ▶ Building Infrastructure for continuous integration, automated software releases, infrastructure automation
- Operating Kubernetes and Docker in production on a public cloud.
- Research of services that are foundational to the product architecture in terms of usage across multiple
- Research for Security tooling of infrastructure and applications to be FedRAMP certification compliant

Devops

NGiNX, US • August 2017 to August 2018



- Research for Kubernetes based cloud infrastructure development
- Container based microservices deployment using Docker, Istio, NGINX as proxy
- Running in Google Cloud platoform
- ▶ CI/CD Pipeline: Jenkins
- ▶ Tools: Zipkin, Prometheus, Grafana, Elasticsearch, Kafka etc.
- Design, develop, and test infrastructure software
- NGINMESH Open Source Project

Cyber Security Research Assistant

Fraunhofer

Fraunhofer, Germany • June 2017 to August 2017

- ▶ Develop POCs: Profinet SIEM, OPCUA SIEM
- Analysis of Securiy Standarts: ISO27001, IEC62443
- Develop Attack, Detection and Prevention Scenarios
- Security Testing of ICS embedded devices and systems
- Technologies: NodelS, Python, Graylog, ElasticSearch, LXC, MongoDB, OPCUA Server & Client

SAP Global Security Research intern

SAP Labs France • August 2016 to February 2017



- Break the attack process at all levels of the attack chain
- Deceive attackers and to increase their cost of attack
- Ensuring the normal flow of operations is not being disrupted
- Honeytoken application Development using Ubuntu, MongoDB, MySQL, NodeJS, VMWare, CloudFoundry, Docker, PHP,CSS, JavaScript, Apache, Yaas, honeypots, firewall, IDS/IPS, proxy

Service Project Manager

Huawei • Baku (Azerbaijan) • Full-time • 2014 to 2015



- Responsible for 24x7 of 5 service providers network(Azercell, Bakcell, Azerfon, Azerconnect, Azertelecom) engineering teams management
- Weekly/Monthly Report to CxO customer levels
- ▶ Technical problems investigation,tracking,escalation with R&D, sales teams
- Interface for change request, complaint handling

System and Network Support Team Leader





- Operation&Maintenance Linux based servers, storage(design, install, integration, configuration, upgrade)
- Network Administration(switch,router,firewall,tap)
- Consulting and presales(customer training, Solution proposal: BOQ,RFP, Maintenance contract, HLD, LLD, PIP, PO, PR, PRP)
- Auditing(find bugs,misconfiguration,leaks, process improvement), Reporting/Training to project team
- Supplier management for projects cost, resource, time matters
- Customer requirements to product/feature transformation
- Reporting customization, use case development
- ▶ E2E New features deployments
- ▶ Interface between R&D and Customer

Wireless/Core network support

ZTE • Baku (Azerbaijan) • Full-time • July 2012 to October 2012



- Kazakstan, Almaty: Altel 4G turnkey network launch Azerbaijan, Baku: Azercell 4G trial network launch
- Scope: Phase 1: 500 eNBs, MME, HSS, SGW, PGW, DNS, ODF, DWDM, FIREWALL, L2/L3-SWITCH, ROUTER
 installation, interconnection, configuration, integration with 3rd parties, acceptance,

Core Network Planning Team Leader

Bakcell • Baku (Azerbaijan) • Full-time • August 2009 to July 2012



- 2G,3G,4G Certified Core network maintenance&planning in mutli-vendor network deployment including CISCO, NOKIA, JUNIPER, MCTEL, HUAWEI:
- Packet Core: SGSN, GGSN, HLR, MME, SGW, PGW, MMSC, SMSC, CBS, NTMS, DIAMETER
 IP BackBone: DNS, FIREWALL, intra&inter communication L3 devices SWITCH, ROUTER
- ▶ Troubleshooting: Wireshark, Cacti, NE Internal logs&tools, vendor-specific OSS tools, open-source tools
- Wireless Network: BSC, BTS, eNB, NB, RNC, MAG, WLC, AP

SKILLS

Management Skills

- Project Planning(cost,resource,time)
- Project Management(Supplier, Customer, Project team)
- ▶ Business Planning and Coordination
- Staff Performance Evaluation

Language Skills

• German(A1) / French(good) / English(fluent) / Russian(fluent) / Turkish(fluent) / Azeri(native)

Technical Skills(+200k USD trainings investment & +10 projects enrollment within 9 years)

- +7 years engineering experience in various IT projects
- ▶ OS: Unix, Windows, macOS
- ▶ Cloud Infrastructure: GCP, Kubernetes, Istio, Docker, CloudFoundry, VMWARE, NGiNX
- ▶ Network: Cisco Cert-CXFF/CCNA Voice/CCDA/CCNA R&S
- ▶ Programming: Python,Shell,C,Rust
- Database: MongoDB, Oracle, MySQL, MSSQL, Sybase, Postgre
- Web Development: NodeJS, PHP, HTML, CSS

EDUCATION

MSc

ITU • Since September 2018

US: Software processes, maintenance, development, modeling, design, implementation, testing and evolution.

MSc

Telecom Paristech, Eurecom • 2015 to 2017

France: Information Security and Communication, GPA 4/4



MBA

Baku Engineering University • 2011 to 2013

IT Management, GPA 4/4

BSc

State University of Petroleum and Industry • 2007 to 2011

Computer Science, GPA 4/4

INTERESTS

Meetup, Bicycle, Zumba, Yoga

• Enjoying share knowledge and experience by attending in different meetups.